Mahmoud Abdelaziz

Front-End / React.js / Full Stack JS Developer



Hello,

I'm Experienced and independent Front End Developer with +3 years of experience integrating the art of design with programming abilities to produce an immersive and engaging user experience through fast website creation, proactive feature optimization, and persistent debugging. Very enthusiastic about aesthetics and user interface design.

Work Experience

3 Oct 2022 - Present

Front End Developer @ U100

- Produced stunning visual elements of web applications by translating UI/UX design wireframes into code while producing high quality, reusable React.js components.
- Built single page applications(SPA).
- Generate static pages with Next.js .
- Ensure efficient web development by supporting designers and app developers while resolving website performance issues.

1 Feb 2022 - 31 Aug 2022

Front End Developer @ One Tech Group - OTG

- Successfully developed store fronts, product listings and improved overall UI and UX to an average increase in sales of 11% for all clients.
- Designed dynamic and browser compatible pages using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, and Javascript.
- Researched emerging web technologies and trends for possible incorporation into sites.
- Made recommendations for new technology integration based on suitability and alignment to business goals.

3 Jan 2021 - 1 Jan 2022

Front End Developer @ One Solution

- UX and business requirements were translated into attractive coding solutions.
- Found bottlenecks and bugs and proposed remedies.
- Assisting back end developers with problem solving and debugging.
- HTML, CSS, Typescript, and JavaScript were used to provide functionality for both mobile and desktop platforms.

1 Sept 2019 - 29 Oct 2020

Tour Operator @ Sonesta

- Personal interactions were established with guests in order to encourage favourable experiences.
- Received and deposited guest payments.
- Created and executed performance improvement strategies and programs to drive continual improvement.

1 Mar 2019 - 29 Aug 2019

Full Stack Developer @ Pay Me

- Bring ideas and suggestions to team meetings and provide updates on deadlines, designs, and improvements.
- Review code, debug issues, and fix issues. Adjust design parameters to incorporate new functionality.
- Consult engineering team members to determine system load and develop improvement plans.
- Work with backend developers to design APIs using Node.js and Typescript.

Contact Information

Form AI Kholig WA Deir on Nohos

Old Cairo,EG,11559
+2012084878080 / +201006936354
mahmoudabdelaziz1993@outlook.com
Linkedin https://bit.ly/3GSkKUu
Portfolio https://bit.ly/3zdpWR4
GitHub https://bit.ly/3auoShk
Codesandbox https://bit.ly/3YZRSSX

Technical Skills

- ★ HyperText Markup Language (HTML)
- ★ Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)
- ★ JavaScript (**JS Es6**)
- ★ TypeScript (**TS**)
- ★ JS Libraries(e.g., React.js, Next.js, jQuery, lodash, momentjs)
- ★ CSS Frameworks(e.g.,tailwindcss, Bootstrap,MUI)
- ★ CSS Preprocessors (e.g., Sass, LESS)
- ★ JavaScript module bundler (e.g., Webpack ,Parcel)
- ★ State management(e.g., ContextApi, Redux)
- ★ Data Fetching Libraries(e.g.,Axios, SWR , React Query)
- ★ Databases(e.g., MongoDB , postgresql)
- ★ Js Back end (e.g., Express ,Next.js ,GraphQL)
- ★ Version Control (e.g., **Git**)
- ★ Js package manager(e.g. ,NPM ,Yarn)
- ★ Responsive Design & Mobile-First Websites
- ★ Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- ★ Performance Testing, Load Testing & Debugging
- ★ Agile Methodology & SCRUM
- ★ backend as a service platforms
 (e.g., Firebase , Supabase)

Education

BSc Degree in Computer Science

Menofia University 28 Jul 2016

Nanodegree in React Development Cross Skilling

Udacity MENA 27 Jul 2022

Languages

- Arabic ★★★★★
- 2. English ★★★★☆